<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Molecular Dynamics on Khayrul Islam</title>
    <link>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/tags/molecular-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Molecular Dynamics on Khayrul Islam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/tags/molecular-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring polyamide nanocomposites: The synergistic effects of SWCNT chirality and maleic anhydride grafting</title>
      <link>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper11/</guid>
      <description>This paper investigates the synergistic effects of SWCNT chirality and maleic anhydride grafting using molecular dynamics simulations to improve the mechanical properties of polyamide nanocomposites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An atomistic study of the tensile deformation of carbon nanotube-polymethylmethacrylate composites</title>
      <link>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper6/</guid>
      <description>This paper uses reactive force field molecular dynamics simulations to study the mechanical properties of SWCNT-reinforced PMMA composites, showing enhancements with varying CNT diameters and volume fractions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coarse-grained molecular simulation of extracellular vesicle squeezing for drug loading</title>
      <link>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper5/</guid>
      <description>This paper uses coarse-grained molecular dynamics to simulate nanopore formation in extracellular vesicles (EVs), providing guidelines for optimizing drug loading efficiency without damaging the EVs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamics simulation of the mechanical properties of CNT-polyoxymethylene composite with a reactive forcefield</title>
      <link>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Khayrulbuet13.github.io/papers/paper1/</guid>
      <description>This paper applies reactive force field molecular dynamics simulations to study the effect of SWCNTs on the mechanical properties of polyoxymethylene (POM) composites.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
